巨齿鲨
弹道导弹核潜艇"野兽"
深海营救任务
看看声纳  有什么发现
Look at the sonar. Let me know what you find.
菲律宾海沟
目前没什么变动  情况越来越糟了
So far nothing new, my friend. It just keeps getting worse.
迪安吉洛  马克斯  回话
D'Angelo, Marks, talk to me.
翻译：灰灰是菇凉
翻译：小酸奶
我们移动到了声纳舱
We've moved to the sonar room.
校对：小酸奶
目前只救出了九名人员
Just nine rescues so far.
后期：8T
情况很糟  是我见过最糟的
It's a mess, man. This is the worst I've ever seen.
救命
Help!
谁来救救我
Somebody help me!
救命  有人吗
Help! Who's there?
又发现一名幸存者
I got one more survivor.
正返回深潜救生艇
Heading back to the rescue vehicle now.
-马克斯  -迪安吉洛
- Marks. - D'Angelo.
怎么回事
What the hell was that?
我不知道
I have no idea.
听
Listen.
乔纳斯  潜艇外面有东西
Jonas, that's something outside the ship.
外面有东西
There's something out there.
起来
Here.
你没事吧
You okay, pal?
老天
Oh, my God.
有东西在撞击船体  快回深潜救生艇
Something's crushing the hull. Get back to the rescue vehicle.
-立刻  -我们马上跟上
- Now. - We're right behind you.
大伙用力拉
You guys, move!
接到了  推过去
Got him. Slide him up.
马克斯  迪安吉洛  汇报情况
Marks. D'Angelo. Report.
快到了吗
You almost here?
乔纳斯  听着  我们困住了
Jonas, listen to me. We're trapped!
什么
What?
碰撞造成舱口被堵
The impact jammed the hatch!
我回去找你们
Coming back.
潜水艇开始崩塌了
The sub is starting to collapse.
-马克斯  -乔纳斯
- Marks! - Jonas!
快下来  不然就太迟了
We need you down here before it's too late.
潜水艇严重损毁
The sub's been breached.
水漫得到处都是
There's water everywhere.
乔纳斯  声纳室里都是水
Jonas, the room is flooding.
马克斯  我们得打开舱口
Marks, we gotta get this hatch open.
快点  乔纳斯  你人呢
Come on, Jonas. Where are you?
-没用的  -救我们出去
- It's not gonna work! - Let us out!
-快点  求求你  -我们需要时间
- Hurry, please! - We just need more time!
乔纳斯
Jonas!
给我们回个话
Let us know when you're here!
别放弃
Don't give up!
乔纳斯  求你了
Jonas, please!
快点下来  你在哪里
Come down here, now! Where are you?
乔纳斯
Jonas!
你疯了
You've lost your mind!
让开  海勒
Back off, Heller.
要是我们回去  所有人都得死
If we go back, everyone dies.
所有人
Everyone.
你都干了些什么
What have you done?
中国上海
五年后
距离中国海岸200英里
"神力一号"科研站
这是在做梦还是怎么的
Are we living the dream here or what?
欢迎来到神力一号  莫里斯先生
Welcome to Mana One, Mr. Morris.
把手给我拿开
Get that thing away from me.
你这是在做什么
What are you doing?
来抱一个  这就对了
Come on, bring it in. There we go.
-很高兴再次见到你  莫里斯先生  -我也是
- Good to see you again, Mr. Morris. - Yeah.
这边请
This way, please.
你闻起来总是很香  用了什么  檀香吗
Hey, you always smell so nice. What is that? Sandalwood?
目前看到的就已经很了不起了
It's impressive so far, I'll say.
她们来了
Oh, here they are.
你还记得我女儿苏茵吗
Do you remember my daughter Suyin?
她是我们的首席海洋生物学家
Our chief marine biologist.
你好
Hi.
很高兴见到脑
他的口音好奇怪呀
抱歉  她说什么
Sorry, what was that?
我没听懂
I didn't catch it.
她说她喜欢你的帽子
She says she likes your hat.
-对  -对
- Oh, yeah. - Yeah.
-走吧  -那走吧
- Let's go. - Why don't we go? Yeah.
你的外孙女是个小机灵鬼
Your granddaughter's a pistol.
好了
Okay.
这里是什么地方
What have we here?
这有点...
This is, um...
太难看了吧
Really ugly.
我知道这里还在建造中
You know, I realize that we're under construction and everything,
但我真的觉得世界一流的研究机构
but I really think that a world-class research institute
必须配上世界级的大门
deserves a world-class entrance.
我再同意不过了
Yeah, I couldn't agree more.
0层到了
O-Level.
欢迎来到0层
Welcome to the O-Level.
漂亮
Nice.
这是我们的中控台
This is our central hub
一旦完工后
from which researchers
将会有五个实验室可供研究者使用
will access all five labs once it's finished.
瞧瞧
Oh, look at that.
这可不是每天都能见到的景象
That's not something you see every day.
是你让鲸鱼们路过这里的吗
Did you have those whales here on cue?
我用了点鲸鱼的"歌曲"来吸引它们过来
I might have lured them with some whale songs.
这是露西和它的女儿格雷茜
This is Lucy and her daughter Gracie.
了不起
Incredible.
潜水控制层
Dive control level.
-到了  -请
- Here we are. - Please.
快些跟上  希望还来得及
Follow me quickly. I hope we are on time.
请进
Come on in.
厉害
Oh, man.
来见一见我们的工程师与潜艇设计师杰克斯
I'd like you to meet our engineer and sub designer, Jaxx.
博士
Hey, Doc.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - Hi.
海勒医生  我们的医疗专员
Dr. Heller. Our medical officer.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
你喜欢看《识骨寻踪》吧
You're like Bones, huh?
这位DJ是我们的远程驾驶员
DJ here pilots our remote explorer.
你好吗
How's it going?
你是我见的第一个亿万富翁
You're my first billionaire.
还有这位  马克是我们的科研站站长
And of course, Mac, our station chief.
莫里斯先生  你来得正好
Mr. Morris, just in time.
这么说我还要继续听
So I keep hearing.
戴上这个
Try that.
来得正好要做什么
Just in time for what?
早上好  莫里斯先生
Good morning, Mr. Morris.
罗莉·泰勒  我们的执潜驾驶员
Lori Taylor, our mission pilot.
你好  莫里斯先生
Hi, Mr. Morris.
欢迎你前来  是我们的荣幸
Welcome on board. It's good to have you.
你好
Hey.
下面情况怎么样
How's it going down there?
你从哪里学到驾驶潜水艇的本事的
Where'd you learn how to pilot a sub?
我在一个拯救鲸鱼的
I spent 10 years with a certain
环保组织工作了十年
whale-saving environmental group
因为法律问题而不便透露名字
that shall remain unnamed for legal reasons.
对  问问她有没有
Yeah, ask her if she ever
用自制鱼雷炸翻过一搜捕鲸船
blew up a whaling ship with a homemade torpedo.
-别瞎说  -不是吧
- Hey. - No.
你挑人的眼光不错
That is a good hire.
两分钟后到达11度
Eleven in two.
水温六摄氏度
Water temperature is at six degrees.
马克  我们正在通过温跃层
Mac, we are through the thermocline.
正接近11000米深度
We are approaching 11,000 meters.
距离海地约100米
One hundred meters from the bottom.
大概
Maybe.
也许吧
Maybe from the bottom.
"也许"  为什么说是也许
"Maybe"? What does he mean, "Maybe"?
跟我来  看看这个
Come on. Look at this.
自1875年以来
Since 1875
我们都相信
we've all believed the
马里亚纳海沟是地球上最深的地方
Mariana Trench was the deepest place on Earth.
我有一个理论  我们认为海洋的底部
I've had a theory that what we think is the bottom
实际上可能是一层硫化氢
might actually be a layer of hydrogen sulfide.
在那片气雾和冰冷的温跃层下面
Beneath that cloud, and a freezing cold thermocline
可能有一个全新的世界
there could be a completely new world.
起源号很快就能证实我父亲的理论
The Origin is about to see if my father is right.
如果下面有暖水
If there is warm water below,
那我们就是第一个看到它的人
that means we're going to be the first to see it.
那要是你错了呢
And what if you're wrong?
那你的13亿就白白浪费了
Then you have wasted $1.3 billion.
你在开玩笑
You're kidding.
他在开玩笑  对吧
He's kidding, right?
收到
Copy that.
慢着  怎么了
Wait. What?
十米  接近边界
Ten meters. Approaching boundary.
悬停于五米处  已停止
Hovering at five meters. Full stop.
最终检测
Final checks.
-杰克斯  -正常
- Jaxx? - Good to go.
-医生  -船员体质正常
- Doc? - Crew are go.
-DJ  -潜艇与探测器正常
- DJ? - Sub and rover are go.
起源号船员
Origin crew,
可以插入
we are go for insertion.
插入
Insertion.
对你们来说什么都可以扭曲成黄笑话吗
Is everything sexual with you guys?
性  食物  力量还有
Sex, food, power and...
钱
Money.
来击个拳
Blow it up now.
潜水控制中心
Dive control,
我们可以插入
we are a go for insertion.
进来了
We're in.
各位  我们进来了
You guys, we're in.
是气雾  没到海底
It's a cloud. It is not the bottom.
罗莉  小心点  我们不知道
Lori, be careful. We don't know the depth
下面有多深
on the other side of this.
海底在你们的头顶上
The sea floor could come right up on you.
收到  马克  我们准备好了
Copy that, Mac. We're ready.
各位  我们进来了
You guys, we are through!
我收到了多个声纳反馈
I have multiple small sonar contacts.
下面有生命体
There is life down here.
恭喜
Congratulations!
部属光源
Deploying the lights.
光源已部属  我去转转
Lights deployed. I'm gonna come around.
我的天哪
Oh, my goodness.
马克  告诉我你收到了画面
Mac, tell me you're getting this.
我们都看到了  罗莉
We're getting all of it, Lori.
大家都很开心
Got a lot of smiling faces up here.
DJ  这个地形可以发射探测器
DJ, we got positive terrain to launch the rover.
收到
Copy.
可以发射
Launch is all yours.
好的
Okay.
探测器
Rover is
已释放
free.
收到
Copy.
水温低于三摄氏度
Water temperature below three degrees Celsius.
这怎么可能
How is this possible?
这个生态系统被冰冷的温跃层
This ecosystem is completely cut off
与其他海洋完全隔绝了
from the rest of the ocean by the freezing cold thermocline.
我们应该能找到
We should find all sorts
完全不为科学所知的各种物种
of species completely unknown to science.
听起来是个不错的投资
Sounds like a good investment.
罗莉  我收到了一个声纳反馈
Lori, I have a contact.
方位080
Bearing zero eight zero.
很大
Huh. It's big.
非常大
Oh, it's huge.
而且它移动得很快
And it's moving fast.
DJ  探测器有视野吗
DJ, is the rover seeing this?
没有  我试试再打开点光源
Negative. Let me try and bring up some more lights.
探测器一号  信号收到干扰
Rover One, signal interrupted.
遥感信号丢失了
Whoa, I just lost telemetry.
怎么回事
What the hell?
起源号  立即右转到305方位
Origin, recommend an immediate right turn to three-five-zero.
可能只是岩块崩塌
This could be a landslide.
我印象中  岩块可不会90度大转弯
Last time I checked, landslides don't make 90-degree turns.
它朝我们来了  朝我们直冲过来了
It's right on us! It's right on us!
这见鬼的是什么东西
What the hell was that?
罗莉  下面发生了什么事
Lori, what's going on down there?
各位
You guys...
-怎么了  -看看这个
- What? - Come look at this.
什么东西能把探测器撞成这样
What could do that to the rover?
我不想知道
I don't think I wanna know.
它又回来了
It's coming back.
天哪
Oh, my God!
我们快走  炸掉沉浮箱
Let's get out of here. Blow the tanks.
我在试  没用
I'm trying. It's not working!
-开不起来  -马克  快帮帮忙
- It's not starting! - Mac, help!
-整个系统都瘫痪了  -天哪
- Whole system's down! - Oh, my God.
天哪  DJ  马克  下面有东西
Oh, my God. DJ, Mac. There's something down here.
乔纳斯是对的
Jonas was right.
乔纳斯是对的  你们收...
Jonas was right! Do you co...
罗莉  回话
Lori, come in.
起源号  能收到吗
Origin, can you hear me?
起源号  请回话
Origin, please respond.
-快啊  -罗莉  回话
- Come on. - Lori, come in.
华尔  能听到吗
Wall, can you hear me?
阿俊
Toshi?
各部门集中一下
Gather around, people. Options.
-不妙  -我们知道他们还活着
- Not great. - We know they're alive.
我还能遥测到他们的生命体征
I've still got telemetry on their vitals.
他们还剩下多少时间
How long do they have?
大概18个小时
Maybe 18 hours.
压载阀卡住了  意味着它不能自行升起
Ballast valves are jammed, which means it can't rise by itself.
如果我们试图拖走它
If we attempt to tow it,
有50%的几率
it's fifty-fifty that the
沉浮箱会爆炸  破坏船体
tanks will explode, and breach the capsule.
-不能对接舱口吗  -不可能
- Can't we go hatch-to-hatch? - Not a chance.
外置摄像头显示舱口严重损坏
The external camera's showing severe hatch damage.
我们必须试一试
We have to try something.
他们在万米深的海底
They're six miles down and no
没有人在这样的深度里展开过营救
one has ever attempted a rescue at that depth.
这不完全正确
Well, that's not exactly true.
不  不可能的
No. No way.
我们做得到的
We can handle this.
在11000米的深度  你们做不到的
Not at 11,000 meters, you can't.
我们在5000米  8000米都成功过
We've gone 5,000 meters, 8,000 meters.
技术到位  深度其实只是一个数字罢了
At some point, it just becomes a number.
为什么不试试这个深度
Why don't you try this number?
三个
Three.
这是在万米以下的海底
That's how many people have
执行过营救行动的人数
actually attempted a rescue below 10,000 meters.
一个
And the number one.
这是活着回来的人数
That's how many are left alive to talk about it.
一个人  乔纳斯·泰勒
One man. Jonas Taylor.
看看那个人上一次
And look what happened to that
去到这个深度时都做了什么
one man the last time he went to these depths.
他救出了11个人  包括你  海勒
He saved 11 people including you, Heller.
-这就是他做的  -他丢下我们的朋友等死
- That's what happened. - He left our friends to die,
因为他得了气压性精神病
because he had pressure-induced psychosis.
得了  海勒  那是你自己诊断的
Come on, Heller. That was your diagnosis.
乔纳斯说有东西袭击了他们
Jonas said something attacked them.
大到能够撞毁一艘核潜艇
Something big enough to take out a nuclear submarine.
-他是个酒鬼  -你没听明白我在说什么
- He's a drunk. - You're not listening!
他正在泰国的海滩上醉成一滩烂泥
He's washed up on a beach in Thailand.
你没在听我说
You're not listening!
-你听到罗莉说什么了  -我在听  我听到了
- Did you hear what Lori said? - I'm listening. I heard it.
-你当时在现场吗  -够了
- Were you there? - That's enough.
我们都听到了罗莉在最后一次传输中说了什么
We all heard Lori's last transmission.
我们必须考虑这种可能性  起源号也许
We have to consider that Origin may have encountered
遇到了乔纳斯·泰勒描述的那种生物
something similar to what Jonas Taylor described.
他有能力逃离的那种生物
Something he was able to escape from.
爸  别这样
Ba! Please.
准备直升机
Prep the helicopter.
我们去泰国
We must go to Thailand.
泰国  北榄府
你的船要弄死我了
Your boat, she's killing me.
第一引擎掉出来了
Number one engine slips out of the gear
液压装置里面还漏水了
and there's some leak in the hydraulics.
我今晚检查一下
Hey, I'll take a look at it tonight.
你昨晚  昨晚的前一晚  前晚的再前一晚
That's what you said last night and the night before that
都是这么说的
and the night before that.
-我会弄好的  -你喝太多了
- Hey, I'm working up to it. - You drink too much.
你这么说
Hey, now you're only saying that
只是因为我现在正好拿着啤酒
because I literally have a beer in my hand.
你啤酒从来不离手
You always have beer in your hand.
知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为我喝太多了
Because I drink too much?
这下变成了一个多事的周二夜晚了
Now this is shaping up to be an eventful Tuesday evening.
你知道我喜欢不请自来
You know I like to make an entrance.
见鬼的  马克  五年过去了
Hell, Mac, after five years,
你出现在我面前就叫不请自来了
just showing up is making an entrance.
怎么  你住在酒吧楼上  真的吗
What? You're living above a bar? Really?
这样你才会登门啊
Figured it was the only way to get you to come visit.
乔纳斯  容我为你引见...
Jonas, allow me to introduce...
很荣幸见到你  张博士
It's an honor to meet you, Dr. Zhang.
我一直很佩服您的研究
Always had a tremendous respect for your work.
你太客气了  泰勒先生
You're too kind, Mr. Taylor.
不是的  你是个好人
Yeah, no, I'm not. You're a good man.
我请你们俩喝啤酒吧
Hey, can I offer either of you two a beer?
因为我要来一瓶
'Cause I'm gonna have a beer.
我们不是来做客的  乔纳斯
It's not a social call, Jonas.
你是说你们不是特意搭直升机来做客的
You mean you didn't helicopter in just to say hi?
我很受伤  马克
You wound me, Mac.
-我们遇到了一个严重的...  -麻烦吗
- We have a serious... - Problem?
料到了
Thought so.
如你所知
Just like you know...
我不搞潜水了
I don't dive anymore.
-我受够了对别人负责  马克  -泰勒先生
- Done being responsible for people, Mac. - Mr. Taylor...
无意冒犯  张先生
Hey, I mean no offense, Dr. Zhang.
要是说这个星球上有谁
I mean, if there was two people on this planet
能让我重返水中
that could get me back into the water,
也许就是你们俩了
it's probably you two.
但你们说不动我
But you can't.
你们告诉我麻烦是什么 然后我就会拒绝
You're gonna tell me your problem and I'll say no.
然后你们会说给我钱
You're gonna offer me money.
我还是会拒绝
I'll still say no.
然后你们想唤起我的良知
You're gonna appeal to my better nature
然而我还是会拒绝
and I'm gonna say no.
因为我没有良知
Because I don't have one.
所以要我说  我们何不坐下来
So I say, why don't we sit down,
好好喝几杯啤酒
we'll enjoy a couple of beers,
然后送你们回去
and then we can get you on your way.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
这是今早发生的
This happened this morning.
我们快走  炸掉沉浮箱
Let's get out of here. Blow the tanks.
我在试  没用
I'm trying. It's not working!
-开不起来  -马克  快帮帮忙
- It's not starting! - Mac, help!
-整个系统都瘫痪了  -天哪
- Whole system's down! - Oh, my God.
天哪  DJ  马克  下面有东西
Oh, my God. DJ, Mac. There's something down here.
乔纳斯是对的
Jonas was right.
乔纳斯是对的  你们收...
Jonas was right! Do you co...
是罗莉
It's Lori.
你的前妻和她的团队困在了11000米深的海底
Your ex-wife and her crew are trapped below 11,000 meters.
我怕他们可能
I fear they may have
遇到了你之前遇到的物种
encountered the same species you did down there.
我有比你欠缺经验的潜水员愿意前去
I have divers with less experience willing to go.
但是我觉得必须让我的团队
But I feel I owe it to my crew
获得最高的被营救成功几率
to give this rescue the best chance of success.
拜托你
Please.
罗莉  把六角扳手给我
Lori, hand me that hexa key.
谢了
Thanks.
好了
Okay.
如果我们把防火墙弄短路
If we can short out the firewall,
我也许就能重启电脑
I can probably reboot the computers.
好 快试试
Okay. Try it now.
辅助动力重新启动了
Auxiliary power's back.
加热器也启动了
Heaters are online.
引擎不可能启动得了
There's no way that we'll get the engine started,
但我们也许可以启动重新压载舱
but we might be able to get the ballast tanks back.
你在干什么  记笔记吗
What are you doing? Taking notes?
给我妻子留封信
Letter to my wife.
以防万一
Just in case.
我们能弄好的
We got this.
一步步来
Step by step.
来  击个章鱼拳
Come on. Give me that fighting octopus.
看到了吗
See?
每次都有用
Works every time.
不
No.
-怎么了  -我们得把灯关掉
- What? - We gotta can the lights.
把灯关掉
Turn out the lights.
下面有别的东西
There was something down there with us.
你的船舱
How can you be sure
没有观测窗  你怎么能肯定这一点
if there were no observation windows on your craft?
因为不管那是什么
'Cause whatever it was
核潜艇的整个右舷都崩塌了
caved in the entire starboard side of a nuclear submarine.
那不是我想象出来的
That wasn't my imagination.
所以你才在营救途中炸毁了舱口
Is that why you blew the hatch mid-rescue?
听着  我把11个人完好无损地救了回来
Hey, look, I brought 11 men back safe and sound.
但因为你慌了  你扔下8个人在那等死
You left eight more to die because you panicked.
要是我不炸掉舱口
If I hadn't blown the hatch,
我们全都会被那生物杀了
we all would have been killed by that thing.
根本就没有什么生物
There was no thing.
没有任何证据能证明它的存在
There was no evidence of anything.
因为它被爆炸摧毁了  海勒
Because it was destroyed in the explosion, Heller.
当时千钧一发
Look, there was no time left!
于是我做了决定
So I made the call!
因为你的怯懦  你留我们的朋友在那等死
And you left our friends there to die in an act of cowardice!
你觉得那下面发生了什么事
What do you think happened down there?
他崩溃了
He lost it.
而现在我们又要把他送去面对同样的情境
And now we're about to send him into the exact same situation.
那个  苏茵
Excuse me, Suyin.
抱歉打扰下  我们需要你
I'm sorry to interrupt you, but we need you.
有紧急情况
It's an emergency.
怎么了  杰克斯
What's wrong, Jaxx?
他们的氧气在泄漏
Now they're leaking oxygen.
他们只有几个小时能撑了  最多多一点
They've got a couple of hours. Maybe more.
-我去  -不
- I'm going. - No.
-等等  什么  -我开水下滑翔器走
- Wait, what? - I'll take one of the gliders,
把起源号拖上来
grab the Origin and tow her up.
等等  要是起源号的压载舱爆炸了
Wait! If the Origin's ballast tanks blow
你也会丧命的
you're gonna die, too.
我们必须试一试
We have to try.
妈妈
Mummy?
梅英
Meiying.
你在这儿啊
我们有些朋友在海底下被困在那里了
妈妈要下去救他们
为什么  我能和你一起去吗
等你长大了
妈妈知道你是妈妈最勇敢的孩子
对吗
妈妈爱你
我也爱你
通讯测试
Communications check!
可以发射
Good to go.
苏茵  可以发射了
Suyin, you are go for launch.
理查德·伯德
Richard Byrd.
启动自动下降序列
Auto descent sequence initiated.
-好啊  梅英  -你好
- Hey, Meiying. - Hi.
-长官  我们又有麻烦了  -是你女儿
- Sir, we've got a new problem. - It's your daughter.
她开了一架水下滑翔器去救他们了
She took a glider to try and save them.
你为什么要让她去
Why did you let her go?
相信我  不是我让她去的
Trust me, I didn't let her do anything.
我有点觉得你应该
I was sort of under the impression you're supposed to
去拯救困在海底的人
try to save people who are dying on the bottom of the ocean.
-这人是谁  -为这一切买单的人
- Who's he? - I'm the guy who paid for all this.
他看起来很英勇  步伐很快
You know, he looks heroic and he walks fast,
但是他的态度有点消极
but he's kind of got a negative attitude.
-还有多少时间  -很少
- What's the window? - It'll be close.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是这里的设计师
I'm the one that designed all this.
这么说我的命在你手上
So my life's in your hands?
差不多吧  有问题吗
Pretty much. That a problem?
没
Nah.
你看起来胸有成竹
You look like you might actually know what you're doing.
潜水控制层
Dive control level.
抱歉等一下
Oh, I'm sorry.
马克  让海勒医生到医疗舱见我们
Mac, have Dr. Heller meet us in the medical bay.
海勒
Heller?
我没提到他也在吗
Did I not mention that?
操你妈
You mother...
他身体状况很好
He's in perfect shape.
就像你上次检查的一样
Just like the last time you examined me.
苏茵15分钟前开水下滑翔器走了
Suyin took a glider 15 minutes ago.
她打算把起源号拉上来
She's planning on taking the Origin back up.
-带我去潜艇  -还没检查完
- Take me to the sub. - We're not done here.
检查完了  罗莉
Yeah, we are. Lori's running
就要没氧气了  而且我们现在在公海
out of air and we're in international waters,
也就是说我可以揍到你妈都不认得你
which means legally I can beat the ever-loving shit out of you
还不犯法
and get away with it.
没错
It's true.
从法律上来说
Legally, I mean.
好在他没有怀恨在心
Good thing he doesn't hold a grudge.
乔纳斯  你知道
Jonas, you do know that
这艘潜艇的设计最深只达12000米吧
this sub is rated for 12,000 meters, right?
就像在海底漏气的那艘吗
Like the one leaking on the ocean floor?
怼得好
Ah. Good point.
-好了吗  -好了
- We good? - Yep.
一旦你脱离安全装置
Once you strip back the safeties
完全手动操控  我知道你肯定会这么做的
and go full manual, like I know you're gonna do,
系统为了跟上
the system's gonna have problems
海底压强变化  就会出现问题
trying to keep up with your pressure changes.
别让压强把你耳朵弄炸了  兄弟
Try not to blow your ears out, brother.
谢了  兄弟
Thanks, mate.
你好  船长
Hello, skipper.
你肯定就是那个疯子了
You must be the crazy guy.
-谁叫我疯子  -我妈妈  还有海勒博士
- Now who called me that? - My mom. Dr. Heller.
好吧  我不是疯子
Yeah, well, I'm not crazy.
我只是看到了别人没看到的东西
I've just seen things no one else has.
那就叫疯子
That's the definition of crazy.
备用动力  备用动力...
Backup power. Backup power...
你父母在哪里
So where are your parents?
我妈妈去海底
My mom's trying to bring our friends back
救我们的朋友了
from the bottom of the ocean.
我爸爸在台北和一个普拉提教练在一起
My dad's with a Pilates instructor in Taipei.
外公说妈妈得往前看
Granddad says Mom needs to move on,
可是妈妈说她需要时间
but Mom says she needs more time
因为她嫁了一个混蛋
because she was married to an a-hole.
感觉你妈妈说得很有道理
Sounds like your mom's got a point.
你懂得挺多
You know a lot.
八岁小孩无所不知
Eight-year-olds hear everything.
我来试试吧
Mind if I give it a try?
再见
Bye.
疯子
Hey, Crazy.
我妈妈会死吗
Is my mom gonna die?
我开泡泡船长过去  你妈妈马上就回来了
I'll have Captain Bubbles and your mom back in no time.
我保证
I promise.
谢谢你  艾玛
Thank you, Emma.
进化号倒数15秒发射
Evolution launch in T-minus 15 seconds.
-DJ  -可以
- DJ? - Yeah.
杰克斯  可以吗
Jaxx, we good?
医生
Doc?
进化号
Evolution,
准备下潜
we are go for dive.
好极了
Fancy.
系统准备下降
System go for descent.
兄弟
Hey, brother.
可以发射了
We're good to go.
系统准备下降
System go for descent.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
系统准备下降
System go for descent.
进化号发射成功
Evolution successful launch.
进化号正通过1000米深度
Evolution now passing 1,000 meters.
警告  进化号二级系统离线
Caution. Evolution secondary systems offline.
他是怎么下潜如此之快的
How is he descending so fast?
他在切断所有不必要的输出
Looks like he's diverted all nonessential power,
像是供热和生命维持设备  以供动力输出
like heat and life support, to the motors.
他会晕过去的
He's gonna black out.
他的血液含氧量在下降
His blood gases are dropping.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
告诉海勒我不会降速的
Tell Heller I'm not slowing down.
苏茵  请注意  进化号正前往
Suyin, be advised. Evolution is now en route.
请立即返回神力一号
Request you return to Mana One immediately.
不  他可以护送我们回去
Negative. He can give us an escort on our way up.
叫她别碍事  马克
Tell her to get out of the way, Mac.
多个人就多份风险  她头脑发热了
More people means more risk and she's in way over her head.
乔纳斯  你说的她都听到了
Jonas, you just told her yourself.
什么
What?
你对讲机上的绿色按钮
The little green button on your intercom,
那个才是用来单通道对话的
that's for single channel communication.
好极了
Brilliant.
进入温跃层
Entering thermocline.
好了  马克  我进来了
Okay, Mac. I am through.
警告  压力负荷接近16000PSI
Warning. Pressure load approaching 16,000 PSI.
在这个速度下  我必须切断取暖器
At this speed, I'm gonna have to divert power from the heaters
和所有可能结冰的东西
and shut down anything that could ice over.
到另一边再打给你们
Call you from the other side.
你这里有无线吗
You got Wi-Fi here?
好了
All right.
Okay.
用力压住
Just keep pressure on that.
-阿俊  它还在外面吗  -我说不准
- Toshi, is it still out there? - I can't tell.
现在什么都看不见
I can't see anything right now.
找到了
There it is.
发现起源号
I've got visual on the Origin.
起源号船体基本完好
I can see most of it.
好  他们还活着
Okay. They're alive.
准备拖船
I'm going to set up to tow.
目标距离  六米  四米
Range to target, six meters. Four meters.
目标锁定
Target locked.
发射磁性尺钩
Firing magnetic hook.
三  二...
Three, two...
苏茵  你还好吗  发生什么事了
Suyin? Are you okay? What's happening?
底下有东西
There is something down here.
有东西撞了我的船
Something just hit my ship.
-苏茵  怎么回事  -是一只巨大的鱿鱼
- Suyin, what's happening? - It's a huge squid.
它绞住了滑翔器
It's got the glider.
压力警报
Warning. Capsule pressure.
马克  它在挤压我
Mac, it's crushing me.
它在挤压我的船  我觉得滑翔器支撑不住了
It's crushing me! I don't think the glider can take it.
支撑不住的
It's not gonna hold.
苏茵  打开压力补偿器
Suyin, engage the pressure compensator.
压力补偿器打开不了
Compensator will not engage.
船体将在10秒内坍塌
Capsule breach in 10 seconds.
船体将在5秒内坍塌
Capsule breach in five...
我的天哪
My God!
是一条鲨鱼
It's a shark.
有20到25米长
It's like 20, 25 meters.
是巨齿鲨
It's a megalodon.
不可能
Impossible.
很高兴我没有疯
So glad I'm not crazy.
苏茵  关掉动力
Suyin, power down.
它有趋光性
It's drawn to the light.
关掉所有系统  不要开灯
Shut everything down and stay dark.
30秒后系统关闭
Shutdown in 30 seconds.
关掉了  但是系统需要时间
Shutting off everything but comms.
它掉头回来了  苏茵
It's circling back. Here it comes, Suyin.
25秒后系统关闭
Shutdown in 25 seconds.
苏茵  没时间了  把灯关掉
Suyin, there's no time. Turn off your lights.
20秒后系统关闭
Shutdown in 20 seconds.
快关掉
Turn them off. Now.
15秒后系统关闭
Shutdown in 15 seconds.
马克  我无法控制
Mac, I have no control.
-快  -十  九
- Hurry. - Ten, nine,
八  七  六  五...
eight, seven, six, five...
你的机会来了  炸掉沉浮箱
Now's your chance. Blow your tanks.
不  我可以帮你救他们
No. I can help you save the crew.
你的滑翔器损坏了  你什么也做不了
Your glider's damaged. There's nothing you can do.
快炸掉沉浮箱
Blow your tanks now.
该死的
Damn it.
张博士  你女儿安全了
Dr. Zhang, your daughter's clear.
我下去找起源号
I'm heading for the Origin now.
目标距离  3米
Range to target, three meters.
海水排离完成
Water extraction complete.
来吧  亲爱的
Let's do this, sweetheart.
这是不是最适合说"我早跟你说了"的时机
Tell me this isn't the world's best "I told you so."
你大老远跑来就为了告诉我你是对的  是不是
You came all the way here just to tell me that, didn't you?
差不多吧
Pretty much.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
看起来不太好啊  准备  一  二  三
That doesn't look good. Ready? One, two, three.
她过来了
She's coming.
快走
Let's move.
要是我们还没脱离的情况下它撞击我们
If that thing hits us while we're still attached...
那我们就都完蛋了
Then we're all gonna die.
快  来
Come on, I've got you.
很危急了
It's gonna be close.
快点  上来
Come on, move, move!
上去  快上去
Go! Go! Go!
我们来不及了
We're not gonna make it.
-来  -阿俊  快点
- Come on. - Toshi, hurry!
阿俊  不
Toshi, no!
对不起
ごめんな。
回话  进化号
Come in, Evolution.
乔纳斯  回话
Jonas, come in.
你们都没事吧
Are you all okay?
海勒医生检测到了罗莉和华尔的生命体征
Dr. Heller has vitals on Lori and The Wall,
但是没有阿俊的
but we don't have Toshi.
阿俊没事吧
Is Toshi okay?
乔纳斯  阿俊没事吧
Jonas, is Toshi okay?
-好了  -慢慢来
- All right. - Nice and easy.
-别动她的脖子  -小心
- Don't move her neck. - Careful.
好  抓稳了  我们接手吧
That's good. Grab a hold. We got her.
你没把阿俊救回来
You couldn't bring Toshi back?
-为什么  -他把舱口关上了
- Why not? - He closed the hatch.
他救了我们
He saved us.
你丢下了他
You left him.
你丢下了他因为你就是这样的人
You left him because that's who you are.
你总是把别人丢下
You are the guy who leaves people behind.
到了那么深的海底  性命全抓在自己手上
You go that deep, you take your life in your hands.
是你送他们下去的
It was your choice to send them down.
就是这样我才不愿意继续了  马克
This is why I don't do this anymore, Mac.
她怎么样
How is she?
穿刺伤刚好避开了肝脏
Well, the puncture just missed her liver.
她失血很多
She lost a lot of blood.
不过情况已经稳定了
But she's stable.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
对不起
I'm sorry.
是我错了
I was wrong.
你救了罗莉
You save Lori,
我们扯平了
we can call it even.
我想为我之前说的话道歉
I just want to apologize for before.
我当时很生气发脾气了  而你救了我的...
I was angry and I lose my temper. And you did save my...
你没穿衣服
You're naked.
我知道你已经尽了全力  谢谢你
I know you did all you could. So, thank you.
嗯
Yeah.
不客气
You're welcome.
我知道当个幸存者的感觉很不容易
I know it's not easy being the person who survives.
我走了  你穿点衣服吧
I'm gonna go now. You should put on some clothes.
对  我刚才正打算这么做
Yep. That's the original plan.
好吧  那就继续吧
Okay, then. Carry on.
我刚才
Hi. Uh... I was...
没事
It's all good.
知道吗  乔纳斯和罗莉的婚姻糟透了
Jonas and Lori were the worst married couple ever, you know?
他们已经离婚一年多了
Whole experiment was over in a year.
我什么都没问
I didn't ask anything.
我知道
I know.
这就是袭击我们的元凶  巨齿鲨
This is what attacked us. A megalodon.
它有多大
How big is that thing?
70到90英尺  折合21到27米
Between 70 and 90 feet, 21 to 27 meters.
巨齿鲨是目前世上最大的鲨鱼
The megalodon was the largest shark that ever existed.
它什么都不怕
It feared nothing.
没有天敌
It had no predators.
它的颌比任何动物都要有力
Its jaws were stronger than any other animal, ever.
巨齿鲨能够拦腰咬穿一头白鲸的骨头
The meg could bite a whale in half, crushing through the bones.
我们这是一片无人海域
We are in uncharted territory.
牙长7.48英尺
在今天之前
Until today,
人们都以为巨齿鲨
megalodons were thought to
在两百万年前已经绝迹了
have been extinct for over two million years.
-错  -一头活化石
- Wrong. - A living fossil.
那头活化石吃掉了我的朋友
That living fossil ate my friend.
我对骏的死也非常难过
I cannot begin to express my sadness for Toshi's death.
这是一生难遇的大发现
We have the discovery of a lifetime.
这就是骏一直以来努力的目标
This is what Toshi worked for.
这是我们所奋斗的目标
It's what we've all worked for.
但我们必须得慢慢来
But we're going to have to proceed slowly.
嗯  我可能没法接受慢慢来
Yeah, that's really not gonna work for me.
神力一号是什么
What is Mana One?
科研站
This station?
是的  它在做什么
Yes. And what's it doing?
我指现在
Hmm? Right now.
没错
Exactly.
什么都没做
Nothing.
两千万的搜查者  没了
$20 million rover, gone.
三千万的潜水艇  没了
$30 million sub, gone.
你们现在正坐在人类历史上
You are now sitting in the most expensive
最昂贵的海洋生物
underwater marine biology day camp
水下夏令营中
in human history.
疯子
Hey, Crazy.
我们现在真的找到了了不起的东西
And now that we've actually found something amazing,
我们不能慢慢来
we can't proceed slowly.
谢谢你信守承诺
Thank you for keeping your promise.
不客气
You're welcome.
你不能因为失去了一名宇航员
You don't quit trying to get to the Moon
而放弃登月
because you lose an astronaut.
你得继续前行
You charge forward
不然别人就会捷足先登
or someone else will get there first.
不管你们乐不乐意  都会有人
Other people will want a piece of this thing,
想要掺一脚
whether we like it or not.
你好像很乐意
You seem to like it.
-什么  -我说你好像很乐意
- Excuse me? - I said, you seem to like it.
不好意思  他也是团队的一员吗
I'm sorry. Is he part of this team?
没错  他就是团队的一员
You're damn right he's a part of this team.
好吧
Okay.
你们有没有想过大自然母亲可能很清楚自己在做什么
You ever think that Mother Nature might know what she's doing?
温跃层的存在可能是有理由的
The thermocline might just be there for a reason?
听着  你要是想探索  那就探索吧
Hey, look, you wanna explore? Go ahead, explore.
但如果你继续往那下面派人
But if you start sending people back down there,
别再让我来擦屁股
don't call me to come save your asses.
如果你还不清楚下面到底发生了什么
Because in case what happened down there wasn't clear to you,
人类对上巨齿鲨碰到的不是恶战
man vs. Meg isn't a fight.
而是屠杀
It's a slaughter.
O层到了
O-Level.
你们所发现的事比我们想象中
What you people discovered is an even bigger goldmine
更大的金矿
than we ever thought possible.
我们根本没有准备好
We are completely unprepared
应对巨齿鲨这样的生物
to deal with creatures like megalodon.
我明白  我们可以做好准备
I understand, and we can get prepared.
我说的是长远的计划
I'm talking about a long-term plan.
那完全是另一种选择
That's gonna be the other alternative.
怎么回事
What's that?
我女儿
My daughter.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
-你看到梅英了吗  -我们找不到梅英
- Did you see Meiying? - We can't find Meiying.
梅英  梅英
Meiying? Meiying?
-我去这边  -我们去这边
- I'll take this way. - Let's try this way.
梅英
Meiying.
Meiying?
-梅英  -妈妈
- Meiying. - Mama.
孩子
你没事吧
Are you okay?
有个怪兽  在看着我们
There's a monster and it's watching us.
没事  只是一条鲸鱼
It's okay. It's just a whale.
等一下  露西呢
Wait. Where's Lucy?
母鲸呢
Where's the mom?
-科研站没事吧  -汇报
- Is the station all right? - Report.
没有漏水  没有肉眼可见的损伤
No leaks. No visible damage.
好的  小队启动紧急应对程序
All right, team. Initiate emergency protocols.
-所有人都不得接近水边  -如果你坚持的话
- And nobody is to go near the water. - If you insist.
关掉所有水下照明
Turn off all the underwater lighting.
让所有船员只在必要区域内活动
Restrict the crew to essential areas.
你说它不可能找到这里来的
You said it was impossible for it to get up here.
应该是这样的
It should have been.
伙计们  来看看这个
You guys, take a look at this.
滑翔器起飞时  隔温层是完整的
When the glider came up, the thermocline was intact,
-所以应该是一摄氏度  对吗  -没错
- so it was one degree Celsius, right? - Yeah.
但是一分钟后  进化号上去后
But a minute later, when the Evolution came up,
问题升高了25度
the temperature increased by 25 degrees.
鲨鱼可以通过这里出来
A shark could come right through there.
这能通过20条
Twenty sharks for that matter.
巨齿鲨撞上起源号后  撞坏了散热阀
When the meg hit the Origin, it slammed into a thermal vent.
每分钟能漏上百万加仑油
Those can release millions of gallons per minute.
阀门的热量
The heat from that vent
在冷冻层中清出了一条路
cleared the path through the freezing cold layer.
你是说我们给巨鲨鱼开了一条高速通道吗
Are you saying we opened up a superhighway for giant sharks?
不完全是  好像只有很短暂的时间
Not exactly. It seems like it was a transitory event.
然后温度就恢复正常  缺口也封上了
The temperatures are returned to normal and the gap is closed.
是的  但是有一只巨大的史前杀戮机器
Yeah. But not before a massive prehistoric killing machine
已经决定跑出来打个招呼了
decided to come up and say "Hi."
听着  我们这是在浪费时间  外面没有东西
Hey, look, we're wasting time. That thing's out there.
我们得找到它  杀了它
We need to find it and kill it.
不
No.
不行  我们得先寻找不需要杀戮的办法
We can't. We should explore non-lethal options first.
对于巨齿鲨来说还是对于我们来说
For the meg or for us?
注意
Attention.
发现一束紧急求救定位光束
I've got an emergency locator beacon.
-南西南方向20英里  -什么意思
- Twenty miles south-southwest. - What does that mean?
说明有一艘船翻了
It means a boat has gone down.
-注意  -三艘船
- Attention. - Three boats.
是那头巨齿鲨  我们得赶紧过去
That's the meg. We need to get there. Now.
马克  我又发现
Mac! I found something!
这些鲨鱼没有鳍
These sharks have no fins.
它们都是被鲨鱼偷猎者杀的
They were killed by shark poachers.
他们割掉鲨鱼的鳍  然后把它们扔回海里等死
They cut off the fins and throw the shark back to die.
就为了一碗汤
All for a bowl of soup.
看来巨齿鲨扳平了比分
Looks like the meg evened the score.
这一切都是一条鱼干的
One fish did all this?
自己问她吧
Ask her yourself.
好吧
Okay.
我们的甲板上有防鲨笼和矛枪
We have a shark cage and spearguns on board.
如果你能射中巨齿鲨的嘴巴或者鳃等柔软的地方
If we can shoot the meg in a soft spot like its mouth or gills,
我们能注射一些致命的毒物
we can inject it with something lethal.
安装防鲨笼得要20分钟
It's gonna take at least 20 minutes to rig the cage.
那家伙两分钟就能跑没影了
And that thing will be gone in two.
为什么不在它身上装个跟踪器呢
Why don't you just put a tracker on it?
你们没看过《鲨鱼周》吗
Don't you guys ever watch Shark Week?
你们可以搞点定位的小玩意
You have one of those, like, GPS tracker tag thingamajigs.
盯住那条鲨鱼  等笼子安装好
Keep an eye on the shark till the cage is ready.
我们应该能往背鳍上发射跟踪镖
We should be able to put a tracking dart in that dorsal fin.
不客气
You're welcome.
是的  但我们得把这艘船开到巨齿鲨边上
Yeah, but somehow we have to get this boat next to that meg.
不  不行
No, we can't.
他很明显对船只很有攻击性
It's already proven aggressive towards boats.
最安全的捷径办法就是不靠任何交通工具
The safest way to approach is without a vehicle.
-等等  等等  -你想找人游过去
- Hold up. Hold up. - You want someone to swim out there?
找一条吃掉我们朋友的史前巨鲨
To a prehistoric shark that ate our friend?
其实  我们一个人下水不会构成威胁
Actually, one of us alone in the water is no threat.
那谁游过去呢
Okay, who the hell is gonna make that swim?
我们来抽签吧
Let's draw straws.
我不会游泳
I can't swim.
对不起  我的本能
Sorry, my body made me say that.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
不怎么确定
Not really.
如果我被吃了  你肯定会很难过
If I get eaten, you're gonna feel really bad.
这根追踪枪只有100英尺的射程
This tracker rifle only has a 100-foot range.
一百英尺
Hundred feet?
一定要靠近了再发射
Get really close before you shoot.
太好了
Great.
如果你想让我去也可以的
If you want me to go instead, I will.
我可以的  马克
I got this, Mac.
太好了  因为我骗你的
Okay, good, 'cause I was lying.
-保重  -谢了  伙计
- Be safe. - Yeah, thanks, pal.
我希望你说的没错
I hope you're right about this.
我也是
Me, too.
我真是个笨蛋
I'm an idiot.
我正在接近一头巨大的杀人鲨
I am proceeding to the enormous killer shark.
我们能接收到  乔纳斯
Yeah, we got you, Jonas.
鲨鱼会被慌张的动作所吸引
Sharks are attracted to panic motion.
保持动作稳定
Keep it nice and smooth.
没事的
It's all gonna be fine.
继续游
Just keep swimming
游  游
Swimming, swimming
继续游
Just keep swimming
天啊  它往水下沉了
Oh, boy, it's going under.
他成功了
He's done it.
马克  追踪器有反应了
Mac, tracker is live!
太好了  把他拉上来  DJ
Great! Reel him in, DJ.
停  停  不要有震动
Stop! Stop! No vibration!
完了  我有麻烦了
Oh, shit. I'm in trouble.
乔纳斯  它冲你来了
Jonas, it's coming at you.
你以为我没有注意到吗
You think I didn't notice?
发动船  发动船
Start the boat! Start the boat!
把他拉上来
Pull him in.
-拜托  拜托  -拜托
- Come on! Come on! - Come on!
你可能的确是个混蛋  但你绝对不是懦夫
You might be a son of a bitch, but you're sure as hell no coward.
干得好
Good job.
我准备了注射埃托啡的标枪
I prepared the spearheads to inject etorphine.
只需要10毫升就能放倒一头食人鲸
A killer whale is knocked out with 10 cc's.
20毫升就能致死  怎么样
Dead with 20. What do you think?
我觉得我们得用上一整瓶
I think we use the whole damn bottle.
再和我说说为什么这算是个好主意
Remind me again why this is a good idea.
怎么了  这是个防鲨笼
What? It's a shark cage.
塑料防鲨笼
Plastic shark cage.
我就当没听见你说的这话
I'm gonna ignore that you just said that.
这个宝贝是聚碳酸酯制的
This beautiful thing is polycarbonate,
专门设计不会开裂  不会碎裂  只会变形
specifically designed not to crack, not to break, but to deform.
而这种厚度的笼子
And in this case, at this thickness,
能承受住每平方英尺两万磅的冲击力
it would take 20,000 pounds per square inch.
如果要打破的话
And if you're talking about breaking,
得需要八九十万磅
that's eight to nine hundred thousand.
我不喜欢
I don't like it.
不喜欢
Doesn't like it.
我肯定不会进去
I wouldn't get in there.
继续放
Keep it coming.
好了
That's good!
他说了什么
What did he say?
他说"小心点"  这是他的"我爱你"
He said, "Be careful." That's his version of "I love you."
你父亲对你很有信心
Your father has a lot of faith in you.
我做过几百次下潜捕鲨了
I've done hundreds of shark dives.
没有像这样的
Not like this.
是的  但我了解鲨鱼的生理结构
Yes. But I know shark anatomy.
我知道能用这个戳破巨齿鲨的哪个部位
And I know where this can penetrate through the megalodon's skin.
苏茵  让我去...
Suyin, let me go instead...
别担心我  让我去做我最擅长的事
Don't worry about me. Let me do what I do best.
一切都没有问题吧
Everything okay up there?
又放了一轮鱼饵下去
Just a fresh round of chum,
所以你尝起来肯定很美味
so you, you know, taste good.
你这么关心我真是太好了
I'm so glad you're looking out for me.
谢谢  再见  祝你好运
Thank you. Bye-bye. Good luck.
下面怎么样了  你没事吧
What's happening down there? You okay?
我没事  只是一些八英尺长的小鲨鱼
Yeah. I'm okay. Just some teeny, tiny eight-foot sharks.
开始吧
Here we go.
我们成功吸引到了她
We've got her attention.
苏茵  它来了
Suyin, it's on its way.
-五十米  -五十米
- Fifty meters. - Fifty meters.
三十
Thirty.
十米
Ten meters.
好了
Okay.
我要试试射它的眼睛
I'm going to try to hit it in the eye.
该死
Damn it.
小心
Whoa! Watch it.
该死
Oh, shit!
太好了  毒素已注射
Yes! The poison is in.
苏茵  坚持住
Okay, Suyin, hang in there.
我被困住了  我在它的嘴里
I'm trapped! I'm in its mouth!
那个笼子是不可能破的
That cage will not break.
这就是问题所在  笼子要被吞下去了
That's the problem. The cage is being swallowed.
-不是又来吧  该死  该死
- Not this again. - Oh, man. Oh, man.
又有问题了  我的面具破了  我在市区氧气
New problem. My mask is broken. I'm losing air.
救命
Help!
快点  杰克斯
Come on, Jaxx!
-谢谢你  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
不  乔纳斯  回船上去
No, Jonas. Go! Get back to the ship.
这里不安全
It's not safe for you.
乔纳斯  回去  乔纳斯
Jonas, go back. Jonas.
乔纳斯  架子掉下去了
Jonas, the crane's in the water!
她会被拉入海底的  快点
It's gonna pull her to the bottom. Hurry!
把备用吊车转过来
Swing the second crane over.
我们要设个陷阱  伙计们  我需要点诱饵
We're gonna set a trap. Guys, I need some bait.
拜托  抓住它
Come on. Got him!
这边
Over here!
这边  扔条绳子
This way. Throw a rope.
她没有呼吸了
She's not breathing.
慢点  你刚刚还没气着呢
Take it easy. You were dead a minute ago.
医生
Doctor.
你把我救了出来
You got me out.
千钧一发
It was closer than I would've liked.
我能和乔纳斯谈谈吗
Can I have a minute with Jonas?
当然了
Sure.
你又一次救了我
You saved me. Again.
我更喜欢你活着
I prefer you alive.
你可能想要看点东西
There's something you might wanna see.
看看谁醒了
Hey! Look who's up.
-你怎么样  -好多了  谢谢
- How are ya? - I'm better. Thank you.
乔纳斯  拍一张我和这头臭怪兽的照片
Jonas, get a picture of me with this big smelly beast.
好了  等等  这样
Okay. Wait. Here.
你想要拍张好的就把头放进去
Hey, you want a proper picture, get your head inside.
-近点  -还要近点
- Closer. - Closer?
拜托  进去
Come on. Get in.
好吧
Okay.
干得漂亮
Nice one.
乔纳斯  拜托告诉我你都拍下来了
Yo, Jonas, please tell me you got that.
我拍下来了  GJ
I got that, DJ.
这一点都不好笑  伙计
That's not funny, man!
不  说真的  很好笑  你看
No, like seriously, it's funny. Look. Watch this.
*我们把肉盾推到水里*
*We got The Wall in the water*
苏茵
Hey, Suyin.
你看他在巨齿鲨边上的照片
Look at him next to the meg.
你还记得O层的咬痕吗
Look, remember the bite marks on the O-Level?
你觉得怎么样
Well, how do you like that?
那真是人类与大自然激战的时刻
That was a serious man vs. Nature moment.
还好最后我们赢了
I'm just glad things went our way.
我们没有赢
It didn't go our way.
对阿俊来说没有
Not for Toshi.
对科学来说也没有
And not for science.
我们做了人类经常做的事  发现  然后毁灭
We did what people always do. Discover and then destroy.
我要弄死你
Hey, I will end you.
至少你可以用这张来做你的约会软件头像
At least you can use this as your dating app pic.
-给你一脚  -没错
- Give you a little leg, you know. - Yeah!
像水母一样
Oh, yeah! Jellyfish.
两条  有两条
Two! There's two?
没人告诉我有两条
Nobody said there were two.
怎么会有两条
How are there two?
救命  把我救上去  救命啊  救命
Help me! Get me out of this water! Help! Somebody help, please!
救命
Help!
你怎么回事
What is wrong with you?
我不会游泳
I can't swim.
不  赶紧上来  认真的吗
No! Get outta here! Really?
别跟我来种族歧视这套
Don't pull that racist stuff on me.
拜托  饶了我吧  我没有种族歧视
Come on, man. Give me a break. I'm not being racist.
你可是在海洋中央工作
You work, literally, in the middle of the ocean.
工作要求中没有这条
This wasn't part of the job description.
这些都不是工作要求
None of this was part of the job description!
他们没写这一条
They left that part out!
爸
我们该找人来帮忙了
It's time to get some real help.
没错  找人来帮忙
Yeah. Go get some help.
我要辞职
I'm quitting.
马克  帮我一把
Mac! Give me a hand.
我需要你找到我的地点
Hey, I need you to find my location.
追踪我的卫星电话  还有一条鲨鱼
Track my sat phone. There's a second shark.
没错  两条  我怎么知道
Yes, two. How the hell should I know?
赶紧找人来帮忙
Just hurry up and get us some help.
-谢谢你  乔纳斯  谢谢  -有什么带什么
- Thank you, Jonas. Thank you. - Bring whatever you got!
放松  放松  不大妙
Just relax. Relax. It's not good.
需要赶紧送他去医院
He needs a hospital fast.
我们得找医生  海勒医生呢
Let's get the doctor. Where's Dr. Heller?
杰克斯
Jaxx?
杰克斯  你没事吧
Jaxx, you okay?
还行吧
Yeah! Kind of.
杰克斯  我们可以的
Jaxx. We can do this.
慢慢地游到船上
Swim gently back to the boat.
慢慢地
Nice and easy.
它来了
Here it comes!
海勒
Heller!
我们不行了
We're not gonna make it.
杰克斯  你不会有事的
Jaxx. You're gonna be okay.
你是个很好的人  杰克斯
You're a good person, Jaxx.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
不要回头
Don't look back.
不
No!
海勒  你在干什么
Heller, no! What are you doing?
来啊
Hey, come on!
Hey! Hey, come on!
海勒
Heller!
快到了
Almost there.
-来  -抓到你了
- Come on. - We got you.
没事的  杰克斯  你会没事的
It's okay, Jaxx. You're gonna be okay.
谢谢你  海勒  谢谢你
Thank you, Heller, thank you.
那是什么  那到底是什么
What was that? What the hell was that?
-好了  拜托  DJ  -不  不
- Okay, come on, DJ. - No! No!
所以我们不能离开科研站  好吗
This is why we don't leave the station, okay?
所以我们不能这样
That's why you don't do that!
你们下去  把它惹毛了
And you went down there and you pissed it off,
现在它要回来把我们都杀了
now it's gonna come back and kill every one of us!
现在我们要怎么办
Now what are we supposed to do?
我一开始就不该出来
I shouldn't even be out here in the first place.
还要在这里游泳  这个吃了那个
Swimming in this ocean. That one ate the other one.
那个还要吃这个吗
Is another one gonna eat this one?
伙计  这
Man, it's...
它刚刚杀了海勒
It just killed Heller.
它杀了肉盾  它杀了阿俊
It killed The Wall. It killed Toshi.
他们都是我的朋友啊
These are my friends, man.
我能说一句吗  这东西正在下沉
Okay, can I just point out that this thing is sinking?
我们现在怎么办
What are we gonna do now?
马克在哪里
Where's Mac?
太好了
Yes!
-你的头发怎么了  -你的头发怎么了
- What happened to your hair? - What happened to your hair?
好冷
Touché.
伙计们
Guys!
那玩意简直是个恶魔
That thing is the devil.
他跟了我们十英里
Ten miles, it's still with us.
你听到了吗
You got us?
大洋  我们在大洋正中央
The ocean. The middle of a freaking ocean!
你觉得如果我们把他扔下去能拖住它吗
Do you think it'd slow down the shark if we threw him over?
你得自己动手
You gotta work on yourself.
好消息  伙计们  复仇的时候到了
Okay. Good news, guys. It's payback time.
太好了
Oh, yeah!
尝尝厉害吧
Yes! Get some!
你真的觉得子弹能伤到那玩意吗
You seriously think that a rifle is gonna hurt that thing?
我一时间也说不了太多
I didn't have much notice,
我只是想要甩掉它
okay? I just wanted to get it off our backs.
好样的  莫里斯
Well done, Morris.
爸爸对不起你
你说什么呢  爸
爸爸对你严厉
对你要求这么高
是因为爸爸知道你的能力
我一直想成为你  想像你一样优秀
但是我
我还是没有做到
爸爸心里你是最勇敢的女儿
你是爸爸这辈子最大的骄傲
爸爸做梦
都想着梅英
长大了能像你一样
别说话了  爸
我懂
没事的
It's okay.
妈妈  妈妈
Mummy! Mummy!
欢迎回来  妈妈
Welcome back, Mummy.
请进
Come in.
梅英怎么样了
How's Meiying?
她很难过
She's sad.
也很困惑
And confused.
你怎么样了
How are you?
我真的不想接受
I really don't want to accept it.
有的时候发生的一些事能改变你的一生
Sometimes things happen that change your life forever.
然而世界还是照常运转
Meanwhile, the world just keeps going.
你以为也许一切能稍微停下来一会
You think maybe it would stop just for a second,
然而并不会
but it doesn't.
你怎么接受的
How do you live with it?
我没有
I don't.
我丢下了我的两个最好的朋友去死
I left my two best friends to die.
每时每刻都萦绕在我脑子里
I think about it all the time.
每天都会在我脑子里重现
Every day I replay it.
我能做到更多吗
Could I have done more?
你不仅仅要看你失去的人
It's not just about the ones you lose.
还要看你所拯救的人
It's also about the ones you save.
我很高兴有你在
I'm glad you're here.
我已经通知了中国政府关于巨齿鲨的事
I've informed the Chinese government about the meg.
还通知了泰国  越南  印度尼西亚
As well as the authorities in Thailand,
以及印度的政府
Vietnam, Indonesia, and Australia.
中国方面要派两艘驱逐舰消灭它
The Chinese are sending two destroyers to take it out.
所以现在这件事正式不归我们管了
So, this is now officially and thankfully out of our hands.
在巨齿鲨被杀死之前
I'm closing Mana One
我要关闭神力一号
until the meg is killed
明早会派疏散船只来接我们走
and an evacuation ship is coming here tomorrow morning.
这才对
You damn right.
最后  我想说
And finally, I just want to say,
我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry for your losses.
你们的朋友们
Your friends.
我本来是来和你们一起庆祝的
I came here to celebrate with you
现在我和你们一起哀悼
and now I'm mourning with you.
谢谢你帮我们擦屁股
Thanks for saving our asses!
你给我带了什么好东西
What do you got for me?
这是塞姆汀高速爆破弹
These are Semtex high-velocity demolition charges.
我让那些人改装了引线  能够有足够的时间沉没
I had the men rig delay fuses to give them time to sink.
这些就是深水炸弹
Essentially, they're depth charges.
这才对
That's right.
我不建议我们这样做
I'm not sure this is a advisable course of action.
被那玩意弄死或弄惨的每个人都是
Every person that gets maimed or killed by that thing
潜在的诉讼
is a potential lawsuit.
潜在的损失
A potential casualty.
放松  伙计  会很有意思的
Relax, bro. It's gonna be fun.
-我能看到你的牌  -看看你们俩
- I can see your cards. - Well, look at you two crooks.
你感觉怎么放
How are you feeling?
跟你的其它人比起来  我还算好的
Like I got off easy, compared to the rest of you guys.
你有什么牌
What do you got up there?
三张K
Three kings.
什么  拜托  每次都这样
What? Come on. Every time.
-你欠我一瓶苏打水  -好吧
- You owe me a soda for that one. - Fine.
等你回来后我们再比  好吗
We'll square up when you get back, okay?
好吧好吧好吧好吧
Fine. Fine. Fine.
我只是想转移一下她的注意力
Just trying to take her mind off things, you know.
她肯定比你要坚强
She's tougher than me, that's for sure.
很抱歉我之前没有相信你
I'm sorry I didn't believe you.
你至少没叫我疯子
Well, you didn't call me crazy.
是啊  但我也没说你是正常的
Yeah, but I didn't call you sane.
我也不常听到别人说我"正常"
Yeah, well, "Sane" Wasn't a word I heard very often.
那现在怎么办
So, what now?
我不知道  可能回泰国吧
I don't know. Go back to Thailand, I guess.
马克和我说了你和苏茵的事
Mac told me about you and Suyin.
-没什么好说的  -也许可以有
- Nothing to tell. - Well, maybe there could be.
你和马克太令人难以置信了
You and Mac are unbelievable.
你不如做点新的尝试
How about you just try something new?
这样你的余生
So the rest of your life
就不会再孤独和悲惨中度过了
isn't a vast wasteland of misery and solitude.
我觉得那是个好主意
I think that's a good idea.
是吗
You do, huh?
八岁小孩无所不知
Eight-year-olds hear everything.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
我妈妈也喜欢你
My mom likes you, too.
这应该是我这辈子最可怕的时刻
This is possibly the worst moment of my life.
接近目标区域
Approaching target area.
我来进行确认
I'll confirm visual.
我先说清楚
Let me make myself absolutely clear.
在直升机杀死那头怪兽之前
We are not getting within a mile of that monster
我们绝对不能接近它
until the helicopter kills it.
我们发现了目标
We have a visual on the target.
停船
Stop the boat.
部署深水炸弹
Deploying depth charges.
炸到它了
We got him.
再炸
Hit it again.
-先生  它不可能  -再炸
- Sir, there's no way possible... - Hit it again.
目标已死亡  重复  目标已死亡
Target is dead. Repeat, target is dead.
你百分百确定吗
Are you absolutely sure?
因为我可不要被什么史前的鱼吃掉
Because I'm not getting eaten by some goddamn prehistoric fish.
确认  先生  它...
Affirmative, sir. There's, uh...
它被炸得粉碎了
Well, there's pieces of it all over the place.
鲨鱼块
Shark chunks?
这是个好迹象
That's a good sign.
好了  带我们过去
All right. Take us in.
跳下去  给我拔几根牙齿
Jump down there, get me a couple of teeth.
要几根大的  放我书桌上
Big ones for my desk.
-好  -你自己也留一根
- All right. - Keep one for yourself.
太棒了
Nice.
你看到了吗
Oh, you seeing this?
太疯狂了
Crazy.
太变态了
That's sick.
真奇怪
That's weird.
拜托  别这么对我
Oh, man! Don't do that to me.
这玩意没有尖牙
That thing doesn't have any teeth.
什么
What?
我觉得我们杀死了一条鲸鱼
I think we killed a whale.
它就在我们下面
It's right below us.
赶紧带我们离开
Get us outta here!
等等  你们这些笨蛋  等等
Wait! Wait, you idiots! Wait!
我在这里  等等
I'm over here! Wait!
不
Oh, no!
我明白  我明白  谢谢
Yeah, I understand. I understand, yep. Thank you.
我来猜猜  莫里斯没给任何人打电话
Let me guess, Morris never called anyone.
没给任何人打过
Didn't call anyone.
没人知道这里有鲨鱼  没人
No one knows the shark's out there. No one.
什么澳大利亚  中国  都不知道
Not the Australians, not the Chinese. No one.
他到底在想什么
The hell was he thinking?
他想让大事化小  小事化无
He wanted to make this go away as quietly as possible.
马克  我们得告诉...
Mac, we need to let everyone...
告诉我所有人  嗯  我在着手处理了
Let everyone know. Yeah, I'm on it.
杰克斯  你能找到那玩意吗
Jaxx, can you find that thing?
等等  你为什么要这样问她
Wait, wait, wait. Why're you asking her that?
我不喜欢你要问她的这个问题
I don't like the fact that you asking her about that thing.
你希望我违法黑入
You want me to illegally
莫里斯的卫星追踪系统
hack into Morris' satellite tracking system
-找到一条史前鲨鱼  -没错
- to find a prehistoric shark? - Yeah.
好的
Okay.
我们用追踪器  找到巨齿鲨
We use a tracker, find the meg,
-再把它杀了  -兄弟
- and we kill it. - Bro.
我们真的要这么做吗
We really gonna do this?
不然很多人都会死  马克
A lot of people are gonna die if we don't, Mac.
-算我一个  -我也是
- Well, I'm in. - Me, too.
来吧
Let's do this.
你觉得我们用疏散船怎么样
How do you feel about commandeering that evac ship?
我觉得
I'd say, uh,
今天是钓鱼的好日子
it's a great day to go fishing.
我们把所有东西都搬上去
Now let's get everything on it.
炸药  滑翔器  全部所有东西
Construction explosives, gliders. The whole lot. Everything.
因为我们要疏散了  对吗  疏散的船
Because we're about to evac, right? Like evacuate?
像正常人一样离开这个无比危险的区域
Like, leave the area of imminent danger
取一个安全的地方
and go to a safe place like normal people?
怎么样  杰克斯  有发现吗
What we got, Jaxx? Anything?
我们看到莫里斯在这里标记了鲨鱼
Yeah. Here's where we saw Morris tag the shark.
但它正在前往这里
But here is where it's going.
-三亚湾  那是什么  -没什么
- Sanya Bay. What's there? - Oh, nothing.
那里只有全世界
It only has some of the
人数最多的海滩
most densely populated beaches in the world.
能联系上政府吗
Any luck with the authorities?
不能  "史前鲨鱼"听上去就像恶作剧电话
No. "Prehistoric shark" Sounds like a damn prank call.
我们没法靠他们
We can't rely on them for anything.
鲨鱼还有多久会抵达有人的地方
How long until the shark gets to those people?
二十分钟
Twenty minutes.
-我们能抢先一步感到吗  -深表怀疑
- Can we get there first? - Doubtful.
必须得去
Yeah, we're gonna have to.
如果我们没有计划  先到也没有意义
Getting there first won't mean anything if we don't have a plan.
也许我们有计划
Maybe we have a plan.
我们要在这个浅滩行动
Here's where we do it. Right here in the shallows.
用滑翔器追踪它
Use the gliders and go after it.
那边明明有一大堆能吃的人
Okay, so, how are we gonna get it here
它为什么要舍弃海滩而来这里
when there's a beach full of people to eat right here?
你请它出来吃晚餐
You ask it out for dinner.
你想来吗
So, how do you wanna do this?
你是在询问我的意见吗
Is that you asking my opinion?
不
No.
我只是客气一下
I was just being polite
然后告诉你我们真正要怎么做
before telling you what we're actually doing,
这样你就能自我感觉稍微好一点
so you feel better about yourself.
谢谢你了
Appreciate that.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
我们准备好了
We're ready.
三亚湾
很漂亮
你们在做什么
你们在捣乱我的婚礼
皮皮
皮皮  回来
Pippin!
妈妈我要去游泳
不可以
为什么啊
太危险了
我就要去
好好好
你可以去游泳  要注意安全
天啊
Oh, my God!
美女
过来一起玩
我们有位子
够近了  停在这里
We're close enough. Stop here.
杰克斯  DJ  我们得把那东西放进水里
Jaxx, DJ, we gotta get that thing in the water.
好的
Yeah, we're on it.
鲨鱼  鲨鱼
Shark! Shark!
所有人都上来
快点  上来
上来
快点上来
快上来
它去哪儿了
有人看到了吗
它不见了
拉我上岸
别丢下我们
它走了
没事了
对我们的计划还有什么最后的意见吗
Any last thoughts about our plan?
不如就从"别死"开始
Not dying would be a good start.
我们终于有意见一致的了  以后还是别这样了
Finally, we agree on something. Let's not make it a habit.
苏茵  小心  快开走
Suyin, look out! Get out of there!
-该死  -怎么了  乔纳斯
- Damn it! - What's wrong, Jonas?
无法开火  离船太近了
Can't make the shot. It's too close to the ship.
上帝啊
Jesus.
乔纳斯  它在你上面
Jonas, it's on you.
马克
Mac!
乔纳斯  下面怎么了
Jonas, what's going on down there?
不想进它的嘴巴
Trying to stay out of its mouth.
上帝啊
Jeez!
苏茵  你好了吗  我来找你
Suyin, are you set? I'm coming to you.
我就位了
I'm in position.
鲨鱼原来越近了  我需要一点空间
Shark's getting close. I need a little breathing room.
-我准备好开火了  -开火
- I'm ready to fire. - Take the shot.
让开  让开
Move! Move!
看那个是什么
去那边
有人看到了吗
Anybody see it?
看不到鲨鱼  但是这里有点不对劲
Can't see the shark, but something's going on up here.
我吸引到它的注意了
Okay, I've got her attention.
把它引到我这里
Bring her to me.
来了
Here we come.
来吧  苏茵
Make your move, Suyin.
尝尝这个吧  你这个丑家伙
Chew on this, you ugly bastard.
不不不  该死
No, no, no! Shit!
上帝啊
Jeez!
小心
不不不  走走走
No, no, no. Go! Go! Go!
-DJ在哪里  -我不知道
- Where's DJ? - I don't know.
-梅英在哪里  -我不知道
- Where's Meiying? - I don't know!
-我哪里都找不到她  -乔纳斯
- I couldn't see her anywhere. - Jonas.
-抱歉  我  -快去  照顾好梅英
- Sorry, I... - Go, go. Take care of Meiying.
乔纳斯
Jonas!
我没事  我再把它引出去
I'm okay. I'm leading it away from the ship.
-天啊  我得  -别拍水了
- Oh, my God! Gotta get... - Stop splashing!
你穿着救生衣呢
You have a life jacket on!
-救生衣  -没错
- A life jacket? - Yep.
没错  我穿着救生衣呢
Oh, yeah. I've got a life jacket on.
就在这里呢  我能...
It's right here. I can...
怪物在这里
The monster's here.
怪物在这里  别担心怪物  有我呢
The monster's here? No, don't worry about the monster, I got you.
-一切都没事  -别说话了
- Everything's fine. - Stop talking.
梅英
Meiying!
妈妈  是你
Mummy! It's you!
太好了  等等  等等  等等我
That's good! Wait! Wait! Wait for me.
等等DJ  等等DJ
Wait for DJ, wait for DJ. Yeah.
-太好了  -上来
- Yes. - Come on.
妈妈  你没事吧
Mummy, are you okay?
我没事
I'm okay.
我也没事
I'm okay, too.
-上来  -上来  -先上来
- Come on. Come up! - Get out of the water!
-梅英  小心  -乔纳斯
- Meiying, be careful. - Jonas!
小心  小心
Careful. Careful.
-它在那里  -天啊
- There it is. - Oh, my God.
乔纳斯
Jonas!
-它要来了  -我们现在完全无法反抗
- It's coming. - We're sitting ducks up here, Jonas.
-妈妈  -它要来了
- Mummy! - It's coming.
-你能听到吗  乔纳斯  -梅英  坚持住
- Can you hear me, Jonas? - Meiying, hold on.
苏茵  我们要走了  这边
Suyin, we're gonna have to go. Through here.
乔纳斯  我们什么都没了
Jonas, we've got nothing left.
几乎什么都没了
Almost nothing.
你要怎么杀死它
How're you gonna kill it?
进化号
Evolution.
我要让它流血
I'm gonna make this thing bleed.
苏茵  你之前说的话没错
Suyin, what you said before, you were right.
不能看着你失去的人
It's not about the people you lose.
而是要看你拯救的人
It's about the people you save.
-下线  -乔纳斯
- Signing off. - Jonas!
来吧
Here we go.
喜欢吗  流血
How do you like that? Bleed!
系统崩溃
拜托  拜托  拜托
Come on, come on, come on.
拜托
Come on.
我们的婚礼没了
你杀了皮皮
太好了
Yes!
谢谢你
Thank you.
让一让  疯子
Beep-beep! Coming through, Crazy.
-你好啊  -看看谁来了
- Hi. - Look who it is.
敬活着
Well, here's to being alive.
敬我们的朋友
And to our friends.
干杯
Cheers.
我不知道你怎想的  但我需要好好放个假
I don't know about you, but, uh, I could use a vacation.
我们要问问我妈妈吗
Shall we ask my mum?